<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Shawn Vause - Shawn Vause's Blog</title><link>https://shawn.vause.us/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Shawn Vause - Shawn Vause's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shawn.vause.us/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Archives</title><link>https://shawn.vause.us/page/archives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shawn.vause.us/page/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Little About Myself</title><link>https://shawn.vause.us/page/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shawn.vause.us/page/about/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://shawn.vause.us/page/about/shawn-and-doc.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A Little About Myself" />&lt;p>My name is Shawn Vause. I am a full-stack software engineer living in Western Pennsylvania and currently working as an Advisory Software Engineer for
&lt;a class="link" href="https://lifevest.zoll.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>ZOLL Lifevest&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on everything from &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_things" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Internet of Things (IoT)&lt;/a> powering
medical devices, serverless cloud architectures using &lt;a class="link" href="https://azure.microsoft.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Azure&lt;/a> and &lt;a class="link" href="https://aws.amazon.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>AWS&lt;/a> and line of business applications
(primarily on the &lt;a class="link" href="https://dotnet.microsoft.com/en-us/apps/aspnet" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>ASP.NET&lt;/a> platform). I started my humble development career doing Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) applications
in SAP using the proprietary ABAP programming language. This blog&amp;rsquo;s content and opinions are my own and mainly for the purpose of helping others with technical
problems and solutions, while documenting them for myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My grandfather was very interested in computers and purchased my first computer for me knowing it was a tool I would need as I progressed with my education. He also encouraged me to
earn my amateur radio license. I am an amateur extra with the callsign AA3YX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got into programming in the &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yahoo!_GeoCities" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>Geocities&lt;/a> era building small websites for bands I enjoyed and video games I had gotten into.
This interest pushed me to persue programming in high school starting with Visual Basic 6.0 and graduating to C/C++. I earned computer science credit in high school through a
collaboration offered with Pitt University. Upon graduation, I attended Penn State University for Information Science and Technology (IST) and earned my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree as
valedictorian with highest distinction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I grew up and continue to live in the same small town I was born in with my wife and boston terrier Doc. While I enjoy my technical hobbies such as programming, gaming, tinkering etc., I
am also getting into fishing to push myself away from the desk from time to time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please feel free to get in touch if you would like to know more, I am happy to chat!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>https://shawn.vause.us/page/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shawn.vause.us/page/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>